ZOE GENEVIEVE LEBLANC

HISTORIAN & DEVELOPER

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I'm currently completing my doctorate in history at Vanderbilt University and recently completed the Nashville Software School Software Developer Bootcamp. I'm interested in opportunities where I can further my knowledge of software development, and utilize my research and communication skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Apprentice Developer, Nashville Software School, 07/2016-03/2017 Intensive software development program covering the full stack. Gained experience in wide range of technologies and software methodologies. Learned technical, project management, and team-based skills.

Teaching Assistant, Department of History, Vanderbilt University, 09/2012-05/2015

Taught undergraduate courses on American, Middle East, and Global history. Responsible for classroom management and lesson plan development. Learned communication, writing, and research management skills.

Web Designer and Office Manager, Contemporary Computers, 12/2010-08/2011

Designed business plan and websites for computer repair store. Learned foundations of computer hardware and website design.

SELECTED PROJECTS

Archivlo 2016-Present

Archival research workflow web app. Connects researchers in archives, and helps them build and share research projects. View: www.archivlo.com

Image Lucida, 2017-Pesent

Image annotation and analysis web app built to help researchers analyze and extract large image datasets. Beta-testing on dissertation research. View: www.github.com/ZoeLeBlanc/image_lucida

Constructing Anti-Colonial Cairo, 2014-Present

Dissertation on the history of global anti-colonialism in the 1950s and 60s through analysis of print media from Cairo, Egypt. Utilizes archival data from multiple countries and languages. View: zoeleblanc.com/dissertation

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in History, Vanderbilt University, 05/2014- Present

M.A. in History, Vanderbilt University, 09/2011-04/2014

Honours Bachelor of Arts with High Distinction, Trinity College, University of Toronto, 09/2006-06/2010

zgleblanc@gmail.com zoeleblanc.com 615.810.6485 Nashville, TN

SOCIAL

▼ TWITTER/ Zoe_LeBlanc

GITHUB/ ZoeLeBlanc

In LINKEDIN/ in/zoe-leblanc

O INSTAGRAM/ zoe-genevieve

SKILLS

Research, problem solving, project management, data analysis, data visualization, networks

HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, Angular, D3.js, Python, Django, Django-Rest-Framework, SQL, Git, Grunt, Browserify, Firebase, Agile Development, GIS

Bilingual in French, reading and writing in Arabic

SELECTED AWARDS

Vanderbilt Digital Humanities Fellowship, 2016-2017

Canadian Social Sciences and Humanities Research Council Dissertation Award, 2014-2016

Nashville Software School Tuition Scholarship, 2016

Vanderbilt Institute of Digital Learning Graduate Fellowship, 2014-2015

Harvard University, Houghton Library Fellowship, 2014

Vanderbilt Graduate Fellowship, 2011-2017